<?xml version="1.0"?>
<publicart xmlns="http://www.nycgovparks.org/bigapps/desc/DPR_PublicArt_001.txt">
 <facilities>
  <facility>
   <name> Humanity Fountain </name>
   <artist> Anne McClain &amp; Friends </artist>
   <from_date> 2010-08-09 </from_date>
   <to_date> 2010-11-05 </to_date>
   <location />
   <description> &amp;#8203;With the knowledge that scent conveys memories and feelings in an impactful way, artist and perfumer Anne McClain created Humanity Fountain, a monument to everyday compassion. The fountain emits a subtle fragrance composed of all natural plant materials (white lotus, sandalwood, mate tea and diluted water).&#160; This exhibition also serves as a backdrop for educational programs by local artists, ranging from natural perfumery and botanical sciences to informative sessions on creative ways to participate in volunteer opportunities in North Brooklyn neighborhoods. For information on these program, visit trustart.org.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Commissioned by &lt;a href=&quot;http://trustart.org/&quot;&gt;TRUST ART&lt;/a&gt;. In collaboration with Lance McGregor, Alan Iwamura, Isaac Tecosky, Facundo Newbery, and Jarek Klim. Supported by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://osanb.org/&quot;&gt;Open Space Alliance for North Brooklyn&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; </description>
   <borough> B </borough>
   <show_large_image> 1 </show_large_image>
  </facility>
  <facility>
   <name> Autumn on the Hudson Valley with Branches </name>
   <artist> Valerie Hegarty </artist>
   <from_date> 2009-11-11 </from_date>
   <to_date> 2010-11-01 </to_date>
   <location> West 20th Street, northern perimeter fence </location>
   <description> Autumn on the Hudson Valley with Branches imagines a nineteenth-century Hudson River School landscape painting that has been left outdoors, exposed to the elements.  The canvas is tattered and frayed, and its partially exposed stretcher bars appear to be morphing into tree branches, as if reverting to their natural state.  The painted portion of the work is based on Jasper Francis Cropsey's &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Autumn on the Hudson River&lt;/span&gt; (1860), a bucolic landscape that shows none of the effects of the Industrial Revolution of its day.  Since the nineteenth century, the Hudson River has been associated with both Arcadian beauty and industrial development, despite the contradiction between the two.  Today, along Manhattan&#8217;s Hudson River, one can view fading remnants of the waterfront as an active shipping port, as well as recent efforts to return it to a more &#8220;natural&#8221; state through the development of park areas and walking paths, including the High Line.  The focus of Hegarty&#8217;s work is the collision of nature and culture, past and present.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This is a project of Friends of the High Line. For more information, visit Friends of the High Line's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thehighline.org/about/public-art/valerie-hegarty%20&quot;&gt;public art page&lt;/a&gt;. </description>
   <borough> M </borough>
   <show_large_image> 1 </show_large_image>
  </facility>
  <facility>
   <name> A Bell for Every Minute </name>
   <artist> Stephen Vitiello </artist>
   <from_date> 2010-06-23 </from_date>
   <to_date> 2011-06-23 </to_date>
   <location> 14th Street Passage between West 13th and West 14th streets </location>
   <description> Artist Stephen Vitiello presents a multi-channel sound installation for which he has recorded bells all over New York City and beyond.&#160; Sounds range from the iconic rings of the New York Stock Exchange bell, the historic Dreamland bell (recorded days after it was discovered in the water off Coney Island), the United Nation&#8217;s Peace Bell, and more everyday and personal sounds of bike bells, diner bells, and neighborhood church bells.&#160; During park hours an individual bell will ring each minute from speakers placed throughout the tunnel space where it will be installed, the overtones fading out as the next bell begins. A chorus of the selected bells will play at the top of each hour, filling the space. The sounds will be represented on physical sound map that identifies the location of each bell, allowing the listener to follow the geographic journey of the recordings.&#160; Collectively, the bells are a microcosm of the urban landscape as they relate to the sounds captured throughout the daily life in New York City. The site becomes activated by the composition, inviting the passerby to engage with the High Line and its connection to the city around it. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This is a project by Creative Time and the Friends of the High Line.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; </description>
   <borough> M </borough>
   <show_large_image> 1 </show_large_image>
  </facility>
  <facility>
   <name> White Ghost </name>
   <artist> Yoshitomo Nara </artist>
   <from_date> 2010-09-07 </from_date>
   <to_date> 2010-11-05 </to_date>
   <location> Park Avenue at 67th Street and 70th Street </location>
   <description> This public art installation coincides with Yoshitomo Nara: Nobody&#8217;s Fool, a major retrospective at the Asia Society from September 9, 2010 through January 2, 2011, and Nara&#8217;s open studio residency throughout August at the Park Avenue Armory. The large sculptures on the Park Avenue Malls stand near the entrances to Asia Society and Park Avenue Armory like komainu, mythical lion-like animal statues commonly placed at the entrance to Japanese shrines as guardians. Nara, who often uses dogs and children as subjects in his work, has uniquely combined the two for White Ghost. The sculptures are glossy white, and sit on rough stone-like bases, referencing how artifacts and monuments from the past often appear in museums. By presenting the sculptures in such a way, he considers the future ruins of his own work, and ultimately his own mortality.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This project is presented by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.artproductionfund.org/&quot;&gt;Art Production Fund&lt;/a&gt; and supported by Marianne Boesky Gallery, Blum &#38; Poe, Kanbar Charitable Trust and Cosmopolitan of Las Vegas.&#160; Exhibitions on Park Avenue are presented with the Sculpture Committee of &lt;a href=&quot;http://fundforparkavenue.org/&quot;&gt;The Fund for Park Avenue&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#8203; </description>
   <borough> M </borough>
   <show_large_image> 1 </show_large_image>
  </facility>
  <facility>
   <name> The Happy Prince </name>
   <artist> Ryan Gander </artist>
   <from_date> 2010-09-15 </from_date>
   <to_date> 2011-02-13 </to_date>
   <location> Doris C. Freedman Plaza, 60th St. and 5th Ave. </location>
   <description> &amp;#8203;&#8220;High above the city, on a tall column, stood the statue of the Happy Prince. He was gilded all over with thin leaves of fine gold, for eyes he had two bright sapphires, and a large red ruby glowed on his sword-hilt.&#8221; So begins the best-known children&#8217;s story by the renowned literary figure, Oscar Wilde (1854&amp;ndash;1900). It seems fitting that British artist Ryan Gander (b. 1976) has taken inspiration for his first public commission from the tale of an enchanted monument. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Here Gander has re-imagined the final, climactic moments of Wilde&#8217;s story where the statue is destroyed. Aided by a friendly swallow, the prince has given away all of his jewels and gilding to alleviate the suffering of the city&#8217;s poor. No longer impressive to city officials, Wilde&#8217;s denuded metal statue is melted down.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In Gander&#8217;s version, the statue appears to be stone; the fallen swallow and the prince&#8217;s indestructible heart lie amidst the rubble. On closer inspection we see that the &#8220;ruin&#8221; is a single massive object: a sculpture of a ruin. In this way, it functions like a plastic toy ruin, at once descriptive and frankly artificial. Gander&#8217;s wry evocation of Wilde&#8217;s tale still resonates in our own period of economic inequality. At the same time, it presents a contemporary approach to sculpture, where the role of the public monument remains an open question.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This is a project by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.publicartfund.org/ryangander/&quot;&gt;Public Art Fund&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt; </description>
   <borough> M </borough>
   <show_large_image> 1 </show_large_image>
  </facility>
  <facility>
   <name> Socrates Sculpture Park EAF 2010 </name>
   <artist />
   <from_date> 2010-09-12 </from_date>
   <to_date> 2011-03-06 </to_date>
   <location />
   <description> &amp;#8203;Socrates Sculpture Park&#8217;s annual emerging artist exhibition is the fruit of the fellowship program, in which up-and-coming artists make outdoor sculpture, many of them for their first time, with the assistance of Socrates staff. The full list of artists includes: Gavin Anderson, Scott Andresen, Rachel Beach, Trenton Duerksen, Jonathan Durham, Daniele Frazier, Frank Haines, Jonggeon Lee, MaryKate Maher, Christopher Manzione, Clive Murphy, Jess Perlitz, Lina Puerta, Jory Rabinovitz, David M. Scanavino, Lior Shvil, Ruby Sky Stiller and Jason Villegas. &#160;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;EAF artists are selected through an open call for proposals and are awarded a grant and a residency in the Park&#8217;s outdoor studio. Fellowship artists are also provided with technical support and access to tools, materials, and equipment to facilitate the production of large-scale public sculptures for exhibition in the Park. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The fellows develop their projects throughout the summer in the open studio and on site in the landscape, offering visitors the opportunity to experience both the creation and presentation of their works. Representing a broad range of materials, working methods, and subject matter, the diverse sculptural works in this exhibition are presented against the Park&#8217;s spectacular waterfront view of the Manhattan skyline. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;For more information, please visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.socratessculpturepark.org/&quot;&gt;www.socratessculpturepark.org&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/sub_newsroom/video/index.html?key=8&quot;&gt;It's My Park segment about Socrates Sculpture Park&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; </description>
   <borough> Q </borough>
   <show_large_image> 1 </show_large_image>
  </facility>
  <facility>
   <name> Myrtle Avenue Bird Town </name>
   <artist> Daniel Goers and Jennifer Wong </artist>
   <from_date> 2010-05-03 </from_date>
   <to_date> 2010-12-10 </to_date>
   <location> Person Square and the NW corner of Fort Greene Park </location>
   <description> Goers and Wong will employ recycled materials and experimental building techniques to add flair to the micro-community of birdhouses.  As colorful and as energetic as the birds that inhabit them, this collection of birdhouses will be the stage for an ongoing performance as birds feed, nest, build, and care for offspring. This exhibition will attract and promote the public to observe their native avian neighbors and the ecological relationship between the birds and the urban environment.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Throughout the duration of the exhibition, Goers and Wong will enact a number of educational workshops, including the South of the Navy Yards Artists stroll in May 2010, in and around the community that will teach children and adults about local bird species and environment awareness. Participants will be encouraged to build their own bird houses with supplies provided by the artists. The installation will also be regularly documented on the exhibition&#8217;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.myrtleavenuebirdtown.com&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;. The artists will provide information and images of the planning, fabrication, and installation, as well as chronicle the lives of the feathered inhabitants of Myrtle Avenue Bird Town.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This is a project of the Myrtle Avenue Brooklyn Partnership. For more information on this exhibition please visit the Myrtle Avenue Bird Town website. </description>
   <borough> B </borough>
   <show_large_image> 1 </show_large_image>
  </facility>
  <facility>
   <name> Viewing Station </name>
   <artist> Richard Galpin </artist>
   <from_date> 2010-05-07 </from_date>
   <to_date> 2011-05-01 </to_date>
   <location> High Line, between 17th and 18th streets </location>
   <description> Richard Galpin alters photographs of cityscapes. His chosen method of manipulation is to cut and remove the top layer of the colored emulsion from his photographic prints, exposing the paper substrate. By eradicating part of the photograph, its imagery becomes transformed to the point of total abstraction. Using clean lines and sharp angles, Galpin&#8217;s technique emphasizes geometric forms, recalling early 20th century art movements such as Constructivism, Cubism, and Futurism. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;For the High Line, Galpin has created a viewing station that functions similarly to his cut photographs. Park visitors are invited to look through the opening on top of the viewing post, which is lined up with a metal screen from which geometric shapes have been cut. The combination of these two devices abstracts the view of nearby buildings. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Through relatively simple means, the viewing station distorts optical perspective, making it difficult to judge spatial distance. Its isolation of fragmented areas encourages more acute observation of surface details, and subtleties of color and texture. The view looks more like a two-dimensional image &amp;ndash; such as a photograph or painting &amp;ndash; than three-dimensional space. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This project is presented by Friends of the High Line. For more information, visit Friends of the High Line's &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thehighline.org/about/public-art&quot;&gt;public art page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt; </description>
   <borough> B </borough>
   <show_large_image> 1 </show_large_image>
  </facility>
  <facility>
   <name> Manolo Valdes on Broadway </name>
   <artist> Manolo Valdes </artist>
   <from_date> 2010-05-20 </from_date>
   <to_date> 2011-01-23 </to_date>
   <location> Broadway, Various locations </location>
   <description> Manolo Valdes on Broadway includes sixteen bronze sculptures along Broadway from Columbus Circle to 166th Street. Each sculpture will include signage that displays mobile phone access numbers for an English and Spanish language audio tour with informative descriptions of the works.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Manolo Valdes is one of the most important and respected Spanish artists working today. Best known for his passion for past masters from Zurbaran to Velazquez, Matisse to Lichtenstein, Valdes uses their work &quot;as a pretext&quot; (&quot;como pretexto&quot;) to create an entirely new aesthetic object. For example, six massive sculptures entitled Reina Mariana, each over eight feet in height and weighing over two thousand pounds, depict Queen Mariana as immortalized by Velazquez. Four of these sculptures with their abstract and simplified forms will grace the famous city landmark, Columbus Circle, as well as two at the south entrance to the 72nd Street subway station. Also sited at the subway station is Odalisca, 2006, a sculpture whose subtle forms refer to works of Henri Matisse and Pablo Picasso. Another highlight of the exhibition is the series of six monumental bronzes &amp;ndash; all over 12 feet in height &amp;ndash; depicting female heads, their calm facial composure and structured equilibrium offset rhythmically by dynamic ornamental head-pieces. The exhibition will also include the New York debut of Valdes' two equestrian sculptures Dama a caballo V, 2008 and Caballero V, 2008, which were inspired by Velazquez's seventeenth-century portraits.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; </description>
   <borough> M </borough>
   <show_large_image> 1 </show_large_image>
  </facility>
  <facility>
   <name> Statuesque </name>
   <artist> Various Artists </artist>
   <from_date> 2010-06-02 </from_date>
   <to_date> 2010-12-03 </to_date>
   <location />
   <description> Public Art Fund brings together a dynamic group of six international artists as they reinvent figurative sculpture for a new era. &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Statuesque&lt;/span&gt; features 10 major works of art by Pawel Althamer, Huma Bhabha, Aaron Curry, Thomas Houseago, Matthew Monahan, and Rebecca Warren. The exhibition is the first time these artists have been shown together, revealing a striking interest in the figure that transcends national boundaries. As the first project curated by Public Art Fund's new Director and Chief Curator Nicholas Baume, &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Statuesque&lt;/span&gt; also marks the New York debut of each work included. In conceiving &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Statuesque&lt;/span&gt;, Baume makes a persuasive argument for the renewed significance of the figure in international contemporary sculpture.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Statuesque&lt;/span&gt; celebrates the return of figurative sculpture, but not in the classical sense. Neither literal portraits nor traditional monuments, these works push the expressive potential of sculptural forms and materials. While the approaches and backgrounds of the artists are very different, their work shares a number of key characteristics. They tend towards abstraction over realism, assemblage over the readymade, construction of form over casting from life, and physicality and texture over refinement of finish. Conceptually sophisticated, historically informed, and expressively direct, &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic;&quot;&gt;Statuesque&lt;/span&gt; finds in the human figure a sculptural tradition ripe for experimentation. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This is a project of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.publicartfund.org/&quot;&gt;Public Art Fund&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; </description>
   <borough> M </borough>
   <show_large_image> 1 </show_large_image>
  </facility>
  <facility>
   <name> Mall-terations </name>
   <artist> Hester Street Collaborative </artist>
   <from_date> 2010-10-01 </from_date>
   <to_date> 2011-09-21 </to_date>
   <location> Allen Street Malls, Manhattan </location>
   <description />
   <borough> M </borough>
   <show_large_image> 1 </show_large_image>
  </facility>
  <facility>
   <name> The Other End of the Line </name>
   <artist> Francis Cape </artist>
   <from_date> 2010-10-22 </from_date>
   <to_date> 2010-11-21 </to_date>
   <location> Gansevoort Plaza </location>
   <description> Inspired by the High Line's history transporting goods from upstate New York into New York City, Cape has transported a previously-occupied residential trailer from Sullivan County, NY to Gansevoort Plaza under the High Line. The trailer's interior will serve as an exhibition space featuring artworks by upstate New York artists, selected by guest curator Ian Berry.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Participating artists include Michael Ashkin, Kenji Fujita, Richard Garrison, DeWitt Godfrey, Matt Harle, Chris Harvey, Margo Mensing, Rebecca Murtaugh, Michael Oatman, Gina Occhiogrosso, Ken Ragsdale, Nancy Shaver, and Alfonso Volo.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Other End of the Line will be on view on Gansevoort Plaza from Friday, October 22 until Sunday, November 21, 2010. This is a project by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thehighline.org/about/public-art&quot;&gt;the Friends of the High Line&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt; </description>
   <borough> M </borough>
   <show_large_image> 1 </show_large_image>
  </facility>
  <facility>
   <name> Scattered Light </name>
   <artist> Jim Campbell </artist>
   <from_date> 2010-10-21 </from_date>
   <to_date> 2010-12-10 </to_date>
   <location />
   <description> Scattered Light is the New York public art debut of pioneering new media artist Jim Campbell. Campbell&#8217;s exhibition features three new major public art commissions, including his largest and most ambitious work to date.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;With Scattered Light, Campbell has hung nearly 2,000 LED lights, encased in standard light-bulb casings, from a massive suspension truss standing 20 feet high and stretching 80 feet down the center of the Oval Lawn. These LEDs have been programmed and sequenced by Campbell to turn and off in such a way that from the pathways of Madison Square Park&amp;mdash;and from the major avenues beyond the park&#8217;s boundaries&amp;mdash;it will appear as though the shadows of people and animals are passing across a massive, gently-undulating amorphous field of light. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Broken Window will be an additional work, situated near the main entrance to Madison Square Park at 23rd Street and Fifth Avenue, in which an array of LEDs encased in a glass-brick wall create illuminated moving images that gently pass across the glass plane. Voices in the Subway Station Eighteen features eighteen glass tablets embedded in the grass that emit gentle pulses of light&amp;mdash;communicating like passengers on the subway. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This is a project of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.madisonsquarepark.org/programs/madsqart.aspx&quot;&gt;Madison Square Park Conservancy&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt; </description>
   <borough> M </borough>
   <show_large_image> 1 </show_large_image>
  </facility>
 </facilities>

</publicart>